Guide to the Barney Rosset papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Barney Rosset papers,
1841-2011
[Bulk Dates: 1935-2011].
Rosset, Barney
68.42 linear ft. (68 record cartons, 1 document box)
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library New York, NY. 10027
MS#1543
7953908
Biographical Note
Maverick and iconoclast American publisher Barney Rosset was born in Chicago in the "year of modernism," 1922. He is chiefly remembered as the owner, publisher, and editor of Grove Press (from 1951 to 1986) and Evergreen Review. In 1940 he spent a year at Swarthmore College and then entered the US Army in 1942. In 1948, after having served as an officer in the Army Photographic Company in China until his return to New York in 1946, Rosset produced Strange Victory, a groundbreaking documentary about postwar racial discrimination in the United States. In 1949, he married the American abstract expressionist painter Joan Mitchell. They later divorced. Rosset was married four more times; his marriages to Hannelore Eckert, Cristina Agnini and Elisabeth Krug ended in divorce. Rosset was married to the former Astrid Myers at the time of this passing.
Acquiring Grove in 1951 while he was still an undergraduate at the New School, Rosset turned the small New York publishing house into one of the most innovative and daring outlet of avant-garde literature, enjoying a heyday of national impact from 1959, when Rosset published the first unexpurgated edition of D.H. Lawrence's Lady Chatterley's Lover, and well into the 1980s. Through Rosset's efforts, in 1964 the Supreme Court granted Grove the right to publish Henry Miller's Tropic of Cancer, which was a landmark case for free speech under the first amendment in the United States. Rosset was instrumental in bringing the works of Samuel Beckett, a lifelong friend, to an American and international audience, beginning in 1952 with the English translation of Waiting for Godot and ending with Beckett's last work, Stirrings Still in 1988 (which he dedicated to Rosset), under the imprint of his new company Foxrock. Under his supervision, Grove published many other key figures of twentieth-century literature and intellectual history on both sides of the Atlantic (and the Pacific), notably William S. Burroughs, Jack Kerouac, Henry Miller, Pablo Neruda, Octavio Paz, Albert Camus, Alain Robbe-Grillet, Egene Ionesco, Jean-Paul Sartre, Frantz Fanon, Alex Haley's Autobiography of Malcolm X, Jorge Luis Borges, Margerite Duras, Jean Genet, David Mamet, Harold Pinter, Tom Stoppard, John Rechy, Khushwant Singh, Will Self, Sherman Alexie, Kenzaburo Oe, Winterson, Yoshimoto.
Rosset also published the magazine Evergreen Review as an adjunct to Grove from 1957 to 1973, and also developed Grove's own film distribution for avant-garde films by directors such as Jean-Luc Godard and Oshima. Through Grove's International Film Festival in New York, Rosset distributed the controversial Swedish film, I Am Curious (Yellow), then breaking all American box office records for foreign films. Other ventures include the Evergreen Theatre Inc., BlueMoon Books, and Foxrock. In 2008, a documentary feature entitled Obscene (Dir. Neil Ortenberg and Daniel O'Connor) about Barney Rosset's life and work was released. Barney Rosset passed away in 2012 at the age of 89.
Scope and Content
The material in this collection was originally housed in binders in Barney Rosset's New York apartment, and cover his personal and professional endeavors as a radical publisher, intellectual, and overall man of letters. It consists of writings, letters, photographs, interviews, films, catalogs, publishing files related to both Grove Press and Evergreen Review, and extensive biographical information on Rosset. The entire collection has been rehoused into archival quality boxes and folders. Each binder had been labeled, generally with some sort of topical or chronological designation. In most cases the binder labels will be retained as file titles, and the subdivisions within binders have become folders and retained, to a great extent, the titles assigned to them by the creator. In some cases the staff of the RBML altered or elaborated on existing folder titles for general clarity and ease of research. In some cases, the collection contains both original and typed (or transcribed) copies, the latter often taking the form of computer printouts that were originally held in binders marked "Master" or "Master Disk" to indicate their contents were on computer disks. These original binder titles have been kept throughout the finding aid.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in VII series:
Series I: Biographical and Early Material, 1936-2003
Series II: Chronological Materials, 1879-2005
Series III: Photographs, 1895-2008
Series IV: Subject Files, 1841-2011
Subseries IV.1.: Grove Press, 1950-2008
Sub-subseries IV.1.1: Grove Film, 1950-2008
Subseries IV.2: Interviews and Articles, 1953-2006
Series V: Samuel Beckett Material, 1935-2006
Subseries V.1: Correspondence, 1935-2007
Sub-sub-series V.1.1.: Beckett Correspondence Project, 1935-2003
Subseries V.2: Related Projects, Works, and Affairs, 1949-2007
Series VI: Audiovisual Material, 1938-2008
Series VII: Files Used for Rosset's Autobiography, 1936-2011
Subjects
Blue Moon Books.; Evergreen review (New York); Grove Press; Grove Press.--Film Division; Grove Press--History--20th century.; Beckett, Samuel, 1906-1989; Burroughs, William S., 1914-1997.; Lawrence, D.H. (David Herbert), 1885-1930.; Miller, Henry, 1891-1980.; Ōe, Kenzaburō, 1 935-; Rosset, Barney.; American literature--20th century.; Beat generation.; Book censorship; Booksellers and bookselling.; Censorship--United States--History--20th century.; Erotica--United States.; Film festivals--United States.; Obscenity (Law)--United States--Cases.; Pornography--United States.; Publishers and publishing.
Access Restrictions
This collection is located off-site. You will need to request this material at least two business days in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
This collection has no restrictions.
Acquisition
Barney Rosset Purchase 9/10/2010 2010.2011.M016
Astrid Rosset Purchase 8/2/2012 2012.2013.M025
Selected Related Material-- at Columbia
William S. Burroughs Papers Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Columbia University
Selected Related Material-- at Other Repositories
The Grove Press Records Syracuse University
Samuel Beckett Papers Harry Ransom Humanities Center
William S. Burroughs Papers Berg Collection, New York Public Library
- Series I: Biographical and Early Material, 1936-2003
  This series is comprised of Barney Rosset's personal, family, and early papers, including documents gathered and created during his high school and college years, and biographical information. Class notes, clippings, correspondence, grades, and materials related to Rosset's early ventures, such as the Anti-Everything Club, can be found in this series.
  - Francis Parker School
    - Chinese History 8th Grade, 1935-936, (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
    - Students, Teachers, Politics, 1935-1940
      - General, 1935-1940, (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
      - "Parker's Little School House" (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - "In Memory of Sarah Greenbaum" (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - "The New Robinson Crusoe" (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - High School English II, III, IV, 1937-1940
      - English II, (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 8-9)
      - English III (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - English IV (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - High School Social Studies and Psychology, 1937-1938
      - Social Studies, (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 12-13)
        - "Sawdust Caesar" (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - Propaganda Report (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - Psychology (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - 8th Grade Anti-(Everything Club) Cover, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Anti-Everything Club Glass Cover (fragile) (Box 65, Folder 1)
    - Biography & Auto-biography (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Rosset, Barnet Sr. Materials, Undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Parker School--Grove Press Correspondence, 1969-1971 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Reunion and Alumni Materials, 1977-1978 1992 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Editorial Clippings from The Parker Weekly and Graders, 1936-1940 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Theater, 1936-1940 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Rosset-Parker School Correspondence, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - General and Alumni-related Clippings, 1977-1979 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Athletics and Track Materials, 1936-1940 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - "Biography/Autobiography: Parker School Years, 1936-1940", (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 27-28)
    - Biographical/Autobiograpical "Parker Material" Outline & Misc., (4 folders) (Box 1, Folder 29-32)
    - Social Studies, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 33-37)
      - "USA" (Box 1, Folder 33)
      - "Russia" (Box 1, Folder 34)
      - "Czechoslovakia" (Box 1, Folder 35)
      - "Fascism/Germany" (Box 1, Folder 36)
      - "China & Japan" (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - High School Records & Assoc./College Records & Assoc.
      - 1936-1937 (Box 1, Folder 38)
      - 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 39)
      - "1939" & "Miscellaneous Francis Parker Records" (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - 1930s Social Scene (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Psychological Test Scores and College Grades, 1937-1946 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Swarthmore, 1940-1941
    - 1941 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Edited Letters and Writings (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Correspondence with Mary Rosset and Barnet Rosset, Sr. (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - W.P.A. Theater and American Student Union's Association at Vassar, 1937-1940 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - The New School
    - Courses, Grades, and Papers, 1950-1951, (3 folders) (Box 1, Folder 47-49)
    - Diploma, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Nancy Ashenhurst--Correspondence, (3 folders) (Box 1, Folder 51-53)
  - "The Strike," circa 1940 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Jack Ellison Correspondence, 1940, (5 folders) (Box 2, Folder 2-6)
  - Alfred Adler Correspondence, 1940-1984, (3 folders) (Box 2, Folder 7-9)
  - University of Chicago Diploma, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Teru Osato Correspondence, 1937-1976, (3 folders) (Box 2, Folder 11-13)
  - "All Our Years" Robert Morss Lovett
    - Edited Text, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Complete Text, 1948, (4 folders) (Box 2, Folder 15-18)
  - Chapter Four--Swarthmore, University of Chicago, UCLA, 1941-2003 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Indianapolis Speedway, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Series II: Chronological Materials, 1879-2005
  This series preserves the creator's chronological arrangement and contains correspondence, writings, personal notes, journals, army documents, interviews, photographs, clippings, ephemera, bibliographic and materials related to Grove Press, as well as extensive intelligence files on Rosset compiled by various branches of American intelligence obtained under the Freedom of Information Act.
  - Pre-1931 to 1934
    - General (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - 1879 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - 1880 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - 1882 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - 1884 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - 1892 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - 1902 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - 1907 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - 1932 "Terrorized at Summer Camp" (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - 1933 "The Black Diaries" and "The Pencil" (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - 1934-1935 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - 1940s Condensed (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Joan Mitchell, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - 1944 Condensed
    - Army Intelligence and Experiences (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Freedom of Information Act Materials & Correspondence with Barnet Rosset Sr. and Mary Rosset (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - October, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - November, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - December, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - 1945
    - January through June (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - "The OSS in World War II," Edward Hymoff (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - General (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - January (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - February (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - March (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - April (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - May (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - June (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - July through December (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Rosset-China, July (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - "China's Greatest Victory," T. White, July (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Correspondence Passantino to Rosset, August (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - August (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Bronze Star and Correspondence Rosset Parents and Military (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - September (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - October (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - James Roosevelt to Mrs. Mary Rosset (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - December (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - 1948
    - "Le Lavandou" (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Joan Mitchell (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Condensed 1948 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - February1948 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - April 1948 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - June 1948 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - July 1948 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - August 1948 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - September 1948 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - October 1948 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - November 1948 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - December 1948
      - "Strange Victory" Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 15)
      - "A Strange Victory in Prague" Condensed Version (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - 1949
    - General (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Condensed (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Barney Rosset Journal (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - "Strange Victory" Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - 1950
    - Grove History (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - General (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Recollections of Jackson Pollock (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - The Beats, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Bibliography and Mrs. Aphra Behn (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Februaryto September, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - October 1950
      - Journal (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - November 1950
      - Journal and Army Intelligence (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - 1951
    - General (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Condensed 1951 (Box 3, Folder 30)
      - Condensed (Box 3, Folder 31)
      - Real Estate, 1951-1952 (Box 3, Folder 32)
      - 1951 East Hampton (Box 3, Folder 33)
      - Buying Grove Circa-1950 (Box 3, Folder 34)
      - 1950-52: Grove Beginnings (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - The New School
      - "Gracie and George" (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Don Allen (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - The Monk (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Rosset Senior and Financial Help (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - 1950 Felix Morrow (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - 1950-1951 First Books [at] Grove (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - 1952
    - General (Diploma and Letter informing of Nancy Ashenhurst's Death) (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Bibliography (Box 3, Folder 43)
      - Melville, Herman--The Confidence Man (Box 3, Folder 44)
      - Lewis, Matthew G.--The Monk (Box 3, Folder 45)
      - Crashaw Verse (Box 3, Folder 46)
      - Aphra Behn (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Condensed Interviews (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - James, Henry--The Golden Bowl (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - 1953
    - General (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - De Sade Selections (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - Cicellis, Kay--No Name in the Street (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - James, Henry--The Sacred Fount (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - Muir, E.--Collected Poems (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - Rodriguet, Raymond--Count D'Orgel (Box 3, Folder 55)
    - Verga, Giovanni--The House by the Medlar Tree (Box 3, Folder 56)
    - Beckett (Interviews) (Box 3, Folder 57)
    - Bibliography (Box 3, Folder 58)
    - Photos (Box 3, Folder 59)
    - Condensed (Interviews) (Box 3, Folder 60)
    - Correspondence
      - March-May (Box 3, Folder 61)
      - June (Box 3, Folder 62)
      - July -December (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - 1954
    - General (Box 3, Folder 64)
    - Bibliography (Box 3, Folder 65)
    - Financial (Box 3, Folder 66)
    - Beckett, Samuel--Waiting for Godot (Box 3, Folder 67)
    - The Maids and Deathwatch (Box 3, Folder 68)
    - Lee, Vernon--The Snake Lady and Other Stories (Box 3, Folder 69)
    - Tutuola, Amos--The Palm-Wine Drunkard (Box 3, Folder 70)
    - Grove History (Box 3, Folder 71)
    - Howard Turner Correspondence, March (Box 3, Folder 72)
    - Rosset Sr. Eulogy and Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 73)
    - Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - 1955
    - Bibliography (Box 3, Folder 75)
    - Rosset Journal January 1st 1955 (Box 3, Folder 76)
    - "The Party's Over Now" Gruen, John (Box 3, Folder 78)
    - Keene, Donald--Japanese Literature (Box 3, Folder 79)
    - Beckett, Samuel--Molloy Cover (Box 3, Folder 80)
    - Lorca Poet in New York (Box 3, Folder 81)
    - Grove Press Finances (Box 3, Folder 82)
    - Milestones (Box 3, Folder 83)
    - Correspondence
      - Beckett, Samuel (Box 3, Folder 84)
      - Cicellis, Kay (Box 3, Folder 85)
      - Mitchell, Joan (Box 3, Folder 86)
    - Singh, Kushwant Correspondence and "Mano Majra" and "Train to Pakistan" Material (Box 3, Folder 87)
    - FBI Memorandums (Box 3, Folder 88)
    - Fred Interview from DELOS-V.Maryland Journal (Box 3, Folder 89)
  - 1956
    - Bibliography (Box 3, Folder 90)
    - Brecht, Bertolt--Threepenny Novel (Box 3, Folder 91)
    - Keene, Donald Anthology of Japanese Literature (Box 3, Folder 92)
    - Grove Finances (Box 3, Folder 93)
    - Condensed (Box 3, Folder 94)
      - January /February (Box 3, Folder 95)
      - Marchthrough May (Box 3, Folder 96)
      - June /July (Box 3, Folder 97)
      - August /September (Box 3, Folder 98)
      - October through December (Box 3, Folder 99)
  - 1957
    - Passport and Rosset Deposition (Box 3, Folder 100)
    - Dreiser, Theodore
      - Dawn and Daily Worker Clippings (Box 3, Folder 101)
    - "A Few Steps from the Long March" (Box 3, Folder 102)
    - Bibliography (Box 3, Folder 103)
    - First Issue of Evergreen (Box 3, Folder 104)
    - Beckett, Samuel--Murphy (Box 3, Folder 105)
    - Bentley, Eric, ed.--The Importance of Scrutiny (Box 3, Folder 106)
    - Hodeir, Andre--Jazz (Box 3, Folder 107)
    - Lawrence, DH--Lady Chatterley's Lover (Box 3, Folder 108)
    - Selby, Hubert--Last Exit to Brooklyn (Box 3, Folder 109)
    - Evergreen Review, Vol. 1, No. 2 (Box 3, Folder 110)
    - Milestones and "Evergreen Review" (Box 3, Folder 111)
    - Passport, History of 96th Division (Box 3, Folder 112)
    - Photos (Box 3, Folder 113)
    - Correspondence
      - Cicellis, Kay (April to October ) (Box 3, Folder 114)
      - Lord, Sterling for Jack Kerouac (January to September ) (Box 3, Folder 115)
      - Beckett, Samuel (January to September ) (Box 3, Folder 116)
      - Grove Press Correspondence
        - John Stark (September to November ) (Box 3, Folder 117)
        - Judith Schmidt and Others (January to December ) (Box 3, Folder 118)
        - Bonnell, M. (October ) (Box 4, Folder 1)
        - Adler, Alfred (August ) (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - 1958
    - Grove History (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Bibliography (Box 4, Folder 4)
      - Artaud, Antonin--Theater and Its Double (Box 4, Folder 5)
      - Beckett, Samuel--Endgame (Box 4, Folder 6)
      - Kazin, Alfred--A Walker in the City (Box 4, Folder 7)
      - Ionesco, Eugène--Four Plays (Box 4, Folder 8)
      - Kerouac, Jack--The Subterraneans (Box 4, Folder 9)
      - Robbe-Grillet, Alain--The Voyeur (Box 4, Folder 10)
      - Waley, Arthur--The Way and its Power (Box 4, Folder 11)
      - Genet, Jean--The Balcony (Box 4, Folder 12)
      - The Wisdom of the East Series (Box 4, Folder 13)
      - A History of Chinese Literature and The Science of Culture (Box 4, Folder 14)
      - Grove Press and the Evergreen Records (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Grove Press Catalog, Fall 1958 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Grove Milestones and Interviews (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence 1958
      - January (Box 4, Folder 18)
      - February (Box 4, Folder 19)
      - March (Box 4, Folder 20)
      - April to June (Box 4, Folder 21)
      - July /August (Box 4, Folder 22)
      - September /October (Box 4, Folder 23)
      - November (Box 4, Folder 24)
      - December (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - 1959
    - Grove Bibliography (Box 4, Folder 26)
      - Cummings, E.E.--100 Selected Poems (Box 4, Folder 27)
      - Delaney, Shelaugh--A Taste of Honey (Box 4, Folder 28)
      - Hughes, Robert, editor--Film: Book I (Box 4, Folder 29)
      - Kerouac, Jack--Mexico City Blues (Box 4, Folder 30)
      - Lawrence, D.H.--Lady Chatterley's Lover (Box 4, Folder 31)
      - Woolf, Douglas--Fade Out (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Grove Milestones and Interviews with Calder, Rembar, and Geller (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Rosset Interview Part II (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Grove History
      - Casement (Box 4, Folder 35)
      - Girodias-Miller--Tropic of Cancer Interview Segments (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - January 1959
      - Caffrey, Raymond T. "Lady Chatterley's Lover" (Box 4, Folder 37)
      - Correspondence (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Correspondence 1959
      - February (Box 4, Folder 39)
      - March (Box 4, Folder 40)
      - April (Box 4, Folder 41)
      - Rosset, Barney, "Giangiacomo Feltrinelli Interviewed: Doctor Zhivago & Censorship" (Box 4, Folder 42)
      - May --Royalties, Trial Materials, and Freedom of Information Act Materials (Box 4, Folder 43)
      - June --"The Car Dealer as Censor" By Max Lerner (New York Post ) (Box 4, Folder 44)
      - July --Freedom of Information Act Materials (Box 4, Folder 45)
      - August (Box 4, Folder 46)
      - September --Freedom of Information Act Materials (Box 4, Folder 47)
      - October --Freedom of Information Act Materials (Box 4, Folder 48)
      - November (Box 4, Folder 49)
      - December (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - 1960s Condensed
    - Interviews Notated (1990s to 2000s), (2 folders) (Box 4, Folder 51-52)
  - 1960
    - Grove Bibliography (Box 4, Folder 53)
      - Allen, Donald M., Editor, The New American Poetry (Box 4, Folder 54)
      - Anderson, Joseph L. and Richie, Donald--The Japanese Film (Box 4, Folder 55)
      - Beckett, Samuel--Krapp's Last Tape (Box 4, Folder 56)
      - Blesh, Rudi and Janis, Harriet--De Kooning (Box 4, Folder 57)
      - Ionesco, Eugen--Rhinoceros and The Killer (Box 4, Folder 58)
    - Fall Grove Press Inc. Catalog, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 59)
    - Correspondence (Box 4, Folder 60)
      - January (Box 4, Folder 60)
      - February/March (Box 4, Folder 61)
      - April and "Barney Rosset: Lady Chatterley's Lover" Playboy Article (Box 4, Folder 62)
      - May (Box 4, Folder 63)
      - June (Box 4, Folder 64)
      - July (Box 4, Folder 65)
      - August (Box 4, Folder 66)
      - September (Box 4, Folder 67)
      - October (Box 4, Folder 68)
      - November (Box 4, Folder 69)
      - December (Box 4, Folder 70)
  - 1961
    - Grove Bibliography (Box 4, Folder 71)
      - Miller, Henry--Tropic of Cancer
        - Cover, Copy, and Anaïs Nin Article (Box 4, Folder 72)
        - Russian--Tropic of Cancer (Box 4, Folder 73)
      - Kerouac, Jack--Pull My Daisy and Timothy Leary Correspondence (Box 4, Folder 74)
      - Aury, Dominique--Literary Landfalls (Box 4, Folder 75)
      - Lindner, Robert--Must You ConformÀ (Box 4, Folder 76)
      - Brecht, Bertolt--Seven Plays (Box 4, Folder 77)
      - Snow, Edgar--Red Star Over China (Box 4, Folder 78)
    - Pinter-related Interviews (Box 4, Folder 79)
    - Adele and Valerie (Box 4, Folder 80)
    - Gertz, Elmer "Frank Harris and Henry Miller--"Two Lives Intertwined with Mine" (Box 4, Folder 81)
    - Correspondence
      - January (Box 4, Folder 82)
      - Timothy Leary, Psilocybin Studies, and Harvard (Box 4, Folder 83)
      - February (Box 4, Folder 84)
      - March (Box 4, Folder 85)
      - April --and Prix Formentor Research Correspondence (1997) (Box 4, Folder 86)
      - May (Box 4, Folder 87)
      - June (Box 4, Folder 88)
      - July (Box 4, Folder 89)
      - August (Box 4, Folder 90)
      - September --w/ Freedom of Information Act Materials (Box 4, Folder 91)
      - October --w/ Freedom of Information Act Materials (Box 4, Folder 92)
      - November --w/ Freedom of Information Act Materials (Box 4, Folder 93)
      - December --w/ Freedom of Information Act Materials (Box 4, Folder 94)
  - 1962
    - Grove Bibliography (Box 4, Folder 95)